recipeland.com 2003-06-22

# Privacy Statement - RecipeLand.com

| |   
---|---|---  
  
#### Privacy Statement

At RecipeLand.com we recognize the importance of your privacy. It's understandable that you may be concerned with the information you provide to us or that is collected by us and how we use it. We've developed the following privacy policy to address any concerns you may have. This policy may be updated from time to time, so please check back occasionally. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at [privacy@recipeland.com](mailto:privacy@recipeland.com). 

**Note to children under the age of 13**   
If you're under 13, you must provide us with written permission from your parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before sending any information about yourself to us over the Internet. 

**Information collected and how it is used**  
RecipeLand.com will use reasonable efforts to prevent the disclosure or use of your personal information. We will not sell, share, or rent your information in any way different from what is disclosed in this statement. RecipeLand.com collects information from you at several different points on our website. This information is used to enhance your experience on RecipeLand.com and as described below. 

**We collect information in the following areas:**

**Registration**   
RecipeLand.com does not collect your personal identifiable information unless you provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. This means we don't require you to register or provide personally identifiable information to us in order to view our site. However, you must register if you wish to use certain features on our site. 

In order to sign up for the following features you must first complete an online registration form. 

  * Recipe Submission
  * Recipe Request
  * MyRecipes Box Features
  * Contest, Promotions and Surveys
  * Coupons and other offers

During registration you are required to give contact information (such as your name and email address). This information is used to provide the services that you have requested, or to contact you about the service on our site for which you have expressed interest. We may contact you from time to time with news as well as for internal marketing and promotional purposes. We NEVER provide this information to 3rd parties. 

**Recipe submission**  
Your personally identifying information may be used for editorial purposes (such as attributing your submitted recipe to you). We may also use this information to contact you should we have any complications with your recipe. 

**Recipe request**  
When you subscribe to this feature, we ask for your name and email address and the description of the recipe that you are requesting. RecipeLand.com then posts your name and your recipe description to the site. The email address you provided is only used for us to contact you when your request has been filled. 

**MyRecipes Box Features**  
When you register to MyRecipes Box, we ask for contact information such as your name, email address. This information is used to provide the login capability for the account. The information collected may be used to allow us to provide you with access to grocery coupons, offers, events and promotions in the your area and/or region. 

**Contest, Promotions and Surveys**  
You must be a registered user in order to enter contests and promotions on RecipeLand.com. Participation in these events is completely voluntary and we do not require you to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as your name and shipping address) and demographic information. Your contact information will be used to notify you if you've won and to award prizes. 

From time to time our site requests information from you via surveys. This information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site and participation is completely at your discretion. 

**Ordering from RecipeLand.com**   
RecipeLand and our e-commerce partners such as PayPal are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. When ordering products from one of our partner sites, information about you is requested on an order form. The information that is collected from you is used to process orders and provide a more personalized shopping experience. RecipeLand.com does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to third parties. 

To find out more detailed information regarding our commerce partner's privacy policies, please click on the links provided below: 

**Security & Safety**  
To take the worry out of using your credit card to order through the web, PayPal use a Secure Server Technology (SSL), which encrypts your information so that it cannot be read as it travels over the Internet. Which means - the characters are scrambled, making it impossible for a third party to intercept your personal information. 

You can verify that the encryption is working by locating the lock icon at the bottom of the web page. While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, as when you are just 'surfing.' All pages within the Marketplace will show the locked icon on the bottom of each page. To learn more about SSL, follow this link to an encryption software authenticator: www.versign.com. 

**Cookies**   
Like most web sites, we use "cookie" technology on our web site. We may place a "cookie" in the browser file of your computer, however the "cookie" itself does not contain any personally identifying information about you. The "cookie" does not track your personal information or provide us with any way to contact you, and the "cookie" does not extract any information off your computer. We use the "cookie" to provide functional information about your browser, allowing us to provide you a better experience. We also use "cookies" to gather broad demographic information and general usage patterns about you and other users of our sites. 

If your browser rejects cookies, you may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that you will be limited from accessing certain areas of our site, such as contests, coupons, MyRecipes Box, shopping list feature, etc. 

**Third Party Advertising**   
We use Burst Media and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that might be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.burstmedia.com/release/privacy.asp). 

**Third Party Cookies**   
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. 

**Log Files**   
Each time a RecipeLand.com page is requested from your browser, we log your computer's IP address into our log files. Your computer has been pre-assigned a 12-digit number. This number is the IP address. We use your IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track your movements on the site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to any other personally identifiable information by RecipeLand.com. RecipeLand.com does not control or monitor whether third parties with web beacons on the RecipeLand.com Web site have the same policy. 

**Other Sites**   
From time to time we may have links to other websites from our site. We do not control, and therefore cannot be responsible for, the collection, use or disclosure of your information by any such third party site. Please carefully review the privacy policy of any third party site that you link to from our site. 

**Security**   
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of your information, RecipeLand.com has put into place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to help safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We use industry standard security measures called SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. 

**Correction/updating Personal Information:**   
At any time, you can update your information by sending an email request to us at: [infochange@recipeland.com](mailto:infochange@recipeland.com). 

In addition, you may notify us if you wish to cease the use of any of your information by sending an email request to the same address and we will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request. 

**Our policies may change.**   
By using our Websites, you consent to the collection and use of your information, as described above, by RecipeLand.com. If we make any changes to our privacy policy, we will post the changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Any changes to our privacy policy will extend to any and all information we may collect or may have collected, regardless of whether the policy was different at the time the information was collected. 

guestbook  
Crockpot recipes  
 **Just for Fun with Quotes** \- [www.FunWithQuotes.com](http://www.funwithquotes.com/)   
from the makers of RecipeLand.com  
At this very moment there are 48479 recipes available.  
Advertising, Legal and Privacy Policy.  
©Copyright 1995-2003 metro.isp Inc. All rights reserved. [gen1](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen1/) [gen1](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen1/) [gen2](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen2/) [gen3](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen3/) [gen4](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen4/) [gen5](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen5/) [gen6](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen6/) [gen7](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen7/) [gen8](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen8/) [gen9](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen9/) [gen10](http://www.recipeland.com/generated/gen10/)
